# Mohammad Abdul Ahad Chowdhury

+61482605155 • ahad@maacpiash.com • www.maacpiash.com • linkedin.com/in/maacpiash • github.com/maacpiash

### PROFILE SUMMARY

Bangladeshi graduate student of data science, with one year of professional experience in full-stack web development. Proficient in developing clound-native web applications (ASP.NET Core, MERN-stack) and machine learning solutions. Currently looking for a part-time, contract, or casual employment in the IT industry.

#### **EDUCATION**

• Macquarie University

Master of Data Science

Coursework: Data Science, Big Data, Machine Learning

Sydney, NSW, Australia February 2020 – May 2022

January 2014 - August 2018

Dhaka, Bangladesh

• North South University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

Capstone project: Fruit Image Classification Using Convolutional Neural Networks

Coursework: Artificial Intelligence, Theory of Fuzzy Systems, Software Engineering, Microprocessor Interfacing & Embedded System, Computer Graphics

Work Experience

• Dynamic Solution Innovators Ltd.

Junior Software Engineer

February 2019 - January 2020

Full-time employment working on Node.js-based full-stack (React.js and Hapi.js) web applications: the <u>OpenCRVS</u> project, and the enterprise solution of <u>Olwel</u>, a healthcare startup. Agile methodology (scrum) was followed. **Responsibilities**: Added features and components; fixed bugs; optimized API calls and database queries; wrote database migration scripts; wrote unit tests. [View the commits for OpenCRVS on GitHub here]

• North South University

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Research Assistant

November 2016 - April 2018

Part-time employment under the Department of Environmental Science and Management. (<u>relevant news article</u>) **Responsibility**: Developed the front-end software (Windows Forms) of NODES, an airline management system.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming languages: C#, JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, Python, C, Java, C++, R
- Web development: ASP.NET Core, Entity Framework Core, SignalR, Blazor, Node.js, Express.js, Hapi.js, Nest.js, React.js, Next.js, Vue.js, Angular (2+), Webpack, PWA, ReST, GraphQL, Socket.IO, Microservices architecture
- Machine learning & data science: Jupyter Notebook, NumPy, Pandas, NLTK, Scikit-Learn, ML.NET
- Desktop app development: Windows Forms, WPF, UWP, Electron.js, JavaFX
- Database systems: MongoDB, MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, SQLite, RethinkDB
- DevOps: Docker, Heroku, Azure App Service, MongoDB Atlas, basic CI/CD

#### Personal Projects

- KonSchool: Fuzzy-AHP-based recommendation system for secondary schools in Bangladesh. ASP.NET Core, Docker, MongoDB [GitHub Azure Heroku Docker]
- Connery: Fruit-image-classifier using convolutional neural networks. ML.NET, ASP.NET Core [GitHub API Swagger]
- AddLicenseHeader: A CLI tool that adds a license header on top of source files. .NET Core [GitHub] NuGet package]
- Vardict: A basic Node.js package for parsing labeled CLI arguments. Node.js, TypeScript [GitHub] NPM package
- **Prospect**: An app for reading the latest posts from popular coding blogs. WIP Node.js, TypeScript, React.js, Next.js, Next.js, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, Docker [GitHub]

## PUBLICATION

- Rahman, N. S. M. R., Chowdhury, M. A. A., Siraj, A.-A. N., Rahman, R. M., Karim, R., & Alam, K. M. A. (2018). Selection of Most Suitable Secondary School Alternative by Multi-Criteria Fuzzy Analytic Hierarchy Process. In: Choroś K., Kopel M., Kukla E., Siemiński A. (eds) Multimedia and Network Information Systems, 279-289. MISSI 2018. Advances in Intelligent Systems and Computing, vol 833. Springer, Cham. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-98678-4 29
- Ashraf, S., Kadery, I., Chowdhury, M. A. A., Mahbub, T. Z., & Rahman, R. M. (2019). Fruit Image Classification Using Convolutional Neural Networks. International Journal of Software Innovation, 7(4), 51–70. https://doi.org/10.4018/ijsi.2019100103
- Rahman, N. S. M. R., Chowdhury, M. A. A., Firoze, A., & Rahman, R. M. (2019). Fusion of BWM and AHP MCDM Methods to Choose the Most Suitable Secondary School for an Individual in the Context of Bangladesh. Vietnam Journal of Computer Science, 06(03), 311–328. https://doi.org/10.1142/s2196888819500167

Last updated on November 23, 2020. Latest version of this document can be found at pia.sh/resume